在中国科技巨头的版图中，很少有人物能像王兴这样具有关键性地位。
In the landscape of China's tech giants, few figures are as pivotal as Wang Xing.
他是美团的创始人，这是一家全球最大的按需配送平台。
He is the founder of Meituan, the world's largest on-demand delivery platform.
但成功并非一蹴而就。
But success didn't come easy.
他的早期职业生涯充满了接连不断的失败。
His early career was marked by serial failures.
他眼看着自己的创业项目一个个倒下，面对不断下滑的数据潸然泪下，但他从未放弃。
He watched his startups collapse, weeping over declining numbers, yet he never gave up.
2010年，他创办了美团。
In 2010, he launched Meituan.
它最初从团购业务起步，后来发展成一款重塑城市生活的超级应用。
It started with group buying but evolved into a super-app that reshaped urban life.
其逻辑简单却强大：
The logic was simple but powerful:
通过一支庞大的骑手队伍，将饥饿的消费者与本地商家连接起来。
Connect hungry customers with local businesses through a vast army of riders.
如今，数百万身穿黄色外套的骑手穿梭在中国的大街小巷，成为城市物流的“血管”。
Today, millions of riders in yellow jackets navigate the streets of China, becoming the veins of the city's logistics.
王兴的愿景并不止于餐饮。
Wang Xing’s vision went beyond just food.
他希望打造“城市生活的操作系统”。
He wanted to build the "operating system for city life."
它成为了一条生命线。
It became a lifeline.
当你生病在家时，骑手可以在几分钟内送来药品。
When sick at home, the riders deliver medicine within minutes.
出行时呢？
Traveling?
你可以即时预订酒店和机票。
You can book hotels and flights instantly.
美团几乎覆盖了日常生活的方方面面。
Meituan covers almost every aspect of daily life.
然而，这种高效率是有代价的。
However, this efficiency comes at a cost.
系统由一套冷酷的算法驱动，为每一单配送计算最短时间。
The system is driven by a ruthless algorithm that calculates the shortest time for every delivery.
骑手往往被困在系统之中。
Riders are often trapped in the system.
为了避免超时罚款，他们被迫与时间赛跑，甚至无视交通规则。
To avoid fines for late deliveries, they are forced to race against the clock, ignoring traffic rules.
这种“速度至上”的需求导致交通事故激增。
This "need for speed" has led to a surge in traffic accidents.
消费者的便利，有时是建立在骑手安全风险之上的。
The convenience of the customer is sometimes built on the safety risks of the riders.
这引发了公众的愤怒和抗议。
This sparked public outrage and protests.
骑手们要求更好的待遇、保险以及更合理的配送时间。
Riders demanded better treatment, insurance, and more reasonable delivery times.
王兴和美团面临着巨大的压力。
Wang Xing and Meituan faced immense pressure.
公众开始质疑：技术是在服务人类，还是在奴役人类？
The public began to question: Is technology serving humanity, or enslaving it?
王兴的事业无疑推动了中国的现代化。
Wang Xing’s work has undeniably modernized China.
但他的故事也为全球敲响了警钟。
But his story serves as a global lesson.
真正的创新不仅仅关乎效率，
True innovation isn't just about efficiency;
更在于在利润与社会责任之间取得平衡。
it's about balancing profit with social responsibility.
这既是王兴面临的挑战，也是整个科技未来的挑战。
This is the challenge for Wang Xing, and for the future of tech.